

Address

Vrouwjuttenland 8a Delft, The Netherlands

Tel & Skype

+31 (0)6 11411955 dade.spadi

Mail

spadini.davide@ gmail.com

Web & Git

www.davidespadini.it github.com/ishepard linkedin/DavideSpadini twitter/davidespadini

Programming



Personal Skills



Davide**Spadini**

Software Engineer & Researcher

About me

I am an Italian Software Engineer & Researcher with a strong background in software development and testing. Currently, I am pursuing a **Ph.D. in Software Engineering at Delft University of Technology (TU Delft), The Netherlands**. Furthermore, my Ph.D. is joint together with a company, SIG (Software Improvement Group), where I work as a researcher.

I actively work on Open-Source projects: I am the author of **PyDriller**, a Python framework for Git. I am very proud of this project: it has been downloaded 6,000 times per month since its release, and many universities/schools teach this tool in their MSR course! Furthermore, PyDriller is used in some companies like SIG and Mozilla.

Experience

2016 - → PhD Researcher

Software Improvement Group

Researcher on test code quality and maintenance, mining software repositories and code review.

2014 - 2015 Websites Administrator

University of Trento

Design and maintenance of all the university's websites

2013 - 2013 Computer Science Teacher

Scuola Easy

Computer Science teacher for a private company. I mainly taught Windows Office, Java and Social Networks.

2011 - 2013 Web Developer

ZeroSeiPlanet

Website creator and administrator.

OSS Projects

2017 - → **PyDriller (Author)**

https://github.com/ishepard/pydriller

PyDriller is a Python framework that helps developers in analyzing Git repositories. With PyDriller you can easily extract information such as commits, modifications, diffs, and source codes. The main libraries used in Pydriller are GitPython and pygit2. I developed Pydriller in Python3.

2019 - \rightarrow **GHLE (Author)**

Released in December 2019.

GHLE is a Google Chrome extension for GitHub and GitLab. It provides new features such as links between test and production code, TDR, detailed code coverage information, and code navigation support. I developed GHLE using mainly Javascript, Typescript, Language Servers, HTML and CSS

2013 - 2015 Pebble Apps and Watchfaces

I wrote many apps and whatchfaces for the smartwatch Pebble. My main whatchface was downloaded 3k times, while my TransmissionTorrent app was downloaded 2k times. I mainly developed them using Javascript, Express and MongoDB.

OS Preference MacOS **** GNU/Linux **** Windows ****

Languages Italian **** English ****

Education

 $07/2016 - \rightarrow$ Ph.D. in Software Engineering

Delft University of Technology / SIG

European project Seneca (http://senecaproject.github.io)

Academic advisor: Dr. Alberto Bacchelli Industry advisor: Dr. Magiel Bruntink

Research Interest:

- Cloud-related testing practices
- Software testing
- Mocking
- · Code reviews
- Collaborative testing

2013–2016 Master's degree in Computer Science

University of Trento

Thesis Title: The Wormhole Peer Sampling Service implemented over We-

bRTC

Advisor: Prof. Alberto Montresor

In collaboration with: Hive-Streaming (Stockholm, Sweden) https://www.

hivestreaming.com Main Topics:

- WebRTC
- · Distributed systems
- · Distributed algorithms
- Network protocols

2009–2013 Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

University of Verona

Main Topics:

- Software Design/Engineering
- · Database Management System
- · Unix scripting
- · Advanced programming
- · Advanced Networking

2005–2009 High school leaving qualification in Computer Science

ITIS G. Marconi

- Basic programming
- Network protocols

2007 - 2008 Internship in the Technical Support Office VOLKSWAGEN GROUP ITALIA S.P.A.

IT support to the employees.

References

Alberto

Bacchelli bacchelli@ifi.uzh.ch

University of Zurich - Professor

Arie Van

Deursen arie.vandeursen@tudelft.nl

TU Delft - Head of the Department of Software Technology

Magiel

Bruntink m.bruntink@sig.eu

Software Improvement Group - Head of Research

Publications

Peer-reviewed journal articles

[1] Mock objects for testing java systems

Davide Spadini, Mauricio Aniche, Magiel Bruntink, Alberto Bacchelli Empirical Software Engineering (2018) pp. 1–38. Springer US.

International peer-reviewed conference papers

[1] Primers or Reminders? The Effects of Existing Review Comments on Code Review Davide Spadini, Gul Calikli, Alberto Bacchelli

Proceedings of the 42nd International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), 2020.

[2] Test-Driven Code Review: An Empirical Study

Davide Spadini, Fabio Palomba, Tobias Baum, Stefan Hanenberg, Magiel Bruntink, Alberto Bacchelli *Proceedings of the 41st ACM/IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering*, 2019.

[3] When testing meets code review: why and how developers review tests

Davide Spadini, Maurício Aniche, Margaret-Anne Storey, Magiel Bruntink, Alberto Bacchelli

2018 IEEE/ACM 40th International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), 2018.

[4] On the relation of test smells to software code quality

Davide Spadini, Fabio Palomba, Andy Zaidman, Magiel Bruntink, Alberto Bacchelli 2018 IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME), 2018.

[5] Software analytics in continuous delivery: a case study on success factors
Hennie Huijgens, Davide Spadini, Dick Stevens, Niels Visser, Arie Deursen
Proceedings of the 12th ACM/IEEE International Symposium on Empirical Software Engineering and Measurement, 2018.

[6] PyDriller: Python framework for mining software repositories

Davide Spadini, Mauricio Aniche, Alberto Bacchelli

Proceedings of the 2018 26th ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, 2018.

[7] Information needs in contemporary code review

Luca Pascarella, Davide Spadini, Fabio Palomba, Magiel Bruntink, Alberto Bacchelli . 2018.

[8] Practices and tools for better software testing

Davide Spadini

Proceedings of the 2018 26th ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, 2018.

[9] To mock or not to mock?: an empirical study on mocking practices

Davide Spadini, Mauricio Aniche, Magiel Bruntink, Alberto Bacchelli Proceedings of the 14th international conference on mining software repositories, 2017.

Honors & Awards

Best Paper Award Honorable MentionInformation needs in contemporary code review

CSCW'18

Certifications

2007 CCNA 1
Cisco Certified Network Associate Exam
2008 CCNA 2

Cisco Certified Network Associate Exam